A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program, Office Files of Anne C. Kubisch, Prudence Brown and Janice Molnar FA666
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program, Office Files of Anne C. Kubisch, Prudence Brown and Janice Molnar
1984-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA666
4.8 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains correspondence and subject files.
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1992-1996; I
  - Prudence Brown Chrons, Jan-Jun 1992 (Box 1)
  - Prudence Brown Chrons, Jul-Oct 1992 (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, Oct-Dec 1992 (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, Jan-Mar 1993 (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, Apr-Jun 1993 (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, Jul-Sep 1993 (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, Oct 1993-Mar 1994 (Box 2)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, Apr-Nov 1994 (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, Dec 1994-Jun 1995 (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, Jul-Dec 1995 (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, Jan-Jun 1996 (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, Jul-Sep 1996 (Box 2)
- Subject Files, 1984-1995; II
  - Urban Poverty Program Reviews 1, 1985-1992 (Box 3)
  - Urban Poverty Program Reviews 2, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
  - Urban Poverty Worldwide Staff Meeting (Cairo), Feb 19-21, 1993 (Box 3)
  - United Nations Conference on Women (1995) -- Planning Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program -- Assessment -- Grants Lists, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program -- Nairobi Meeting, Jul 1985 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program -- October 7, 1985 Meeting, Oct 7, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum, 1986-1994 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum -- Ford Foundation Annual Report, Nairobi Women's Conference RGA, Meetings Memoranda, etc., 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum -- Ford Foundation Newsletter, Mar 1989 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum Symposium -- Incl. "The Changing Context for Movements to Improve Women's Lives", Sep 29, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #1 -- Ford Foundation Work/Family, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #1 -- Survey, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #1, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #2, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #2 -- Survey Feedback -- Preliminary Draft, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #3 -- Meetings, Notes, Report, etc., 1988-1990 (Box 4)